Finding aid for the Paul Monette papers, 1945-1995 LSC.1707
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 2: Biographical
  - Subseries 2.7: Memorial Items
    - Correspondences to WW: Re: AIDS Quilt Panel, etc.: Most with enclosures., Contain snapshots, programs, etc. (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      Letters from: Barbara Abbott, Robert Adams, Edgar Anderson, Jay Anderson, Steven Bach, Jeff Baron, Elaine Mullen Barrett.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      Letters from: Martin Beadle & Douglas Bowers, Nancy Bereano, Sascha Bittner, Gloria Bjerregaard, Star Black, Gay Block, Janice Blum.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      Letters from: Tom Brandeberry, Noel Briscoe, Jeffrey Brody, Tom Bubnack, Peter Bunnell, Susan Byers.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      Letters from: Tita Caldwell, Bruce Christopher Carr, David Castro, Srah Chambers, Otis Charles, Mr / Mrs Chasanoff, Irvin Chen.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      Letters from: Diana Cobbold, David Cohen, Bernie Copper and Brian Miller, Judy Cox, Donico Croom, Jack Daley.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      Letters from: Davis Dassori, Bob Davis, John DeMarzo, Michael Denneny, Frank DeSarro, Joel Dillard, Bruce Donnell.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      Letters from: Chris Downing, David Drake, Dorothy Eisenhour, Rev. Wayne Elliott, Gita Endore, David Eye.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 8)
      Letters from: Harry Faddis, Marcia Finks, Ben Fowler, Ganymede, Christopher Gates, Harlan Greene, David Groff.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 9)
      Letters from: Spence Halperin, Cathy Hauer, Laurie Hauer, Jane Haynes, Philip Himberg, Bernice Horwitz.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      Letters from: Terry House, Marcia Hunt, Tom Hyland, Stacey Ingber, Ed Ingebretsen, Richard Isay.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      Letters from: Mikki Jackson, Sally Jackson, Rich Jennings and Jerome Brown, Jim Jensen, Toby Johnson, Heidi Jones.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      Letters from: Keith Kahla, Greg Kahn, Craig Cain, Mark Katz, Martin Katz, Roger Kaufman, Gary Thomas Keating, Michael Kearns.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 13)
      Letters from: Owen Keehnen, Paul Kellogg, Lisa Kenecht, Rudy Kikel and Sterling Giles, Linda Kish, Yuji Kitamaru, William Koelsch (A. Nolder Gay).
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 1)
      Letters from: Dan Lashen, Norman Laurila, Barbara Lebson, Christina Lemonias, Coy Ludwig, Nunizo Lupo.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      Letters from: Lee MacNeil, Kerry and Kiffen Madden-Lunsford, Richard Maloy, Robert Manners, Mary Marks, Sybil McCarthy, J.D. (Sandy) McClatchy.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      Letters from: Joan McGuire, Susan McHenry, Ian McKellen, Deacon and Mrs. Meader, Peter Metcalf, Rondo Mieczkowski and D. Barillaro, Tim Miller.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 4)
      Letters from: Linda Montague, Mark Morewitz, Lynn Morgan, John Morris and Doug Rochelle, Mary Nalick, Peter Nardi, Tom Nash, Neon, Vincent Newton.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 5)
      Letters from: Elisabeth Nonas, Kevin O'Donnell, Fr. Juan Oliver, Merle Panick, John Paoletti, Ben Perkins, Gitta Perl, David J. Peters, Kim Powers.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 6)
      Letters from: Diane Put, Paul Reed, Rob Remer, Ruby Ritchie, Mary Roberts, Douglas Rorapaugh, Jerome Rousseau.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 7)
      Letters from: Barbara Safrin, Edgar Sandulo, Frances Sawaya, Pat Scarola, Sam Schad, Terry Schaefer, Marilyn Schindler.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 8)
      Letters from: Jackie Schwartz, Greg and Gene Scott, David Seinfeld, Jeffrey Sherman, Don Shewey, Charlotte Shifrin, Norma Shifrin.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 9)
      Letters from: Beth and Joe Simon, Fr. Tony Smith, Dolores Snow, Ruth Spiegel, Starcross Community, Stuart Jason, Gail Suber.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 10)
      Letters from: Ginny Thomason, Grace Trepodi, David Tripp, Richard Trousdell.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 11)
      Letters from: Ron Wakabayashi, Patricia Nell Warren, Tom Watson, James Weiss, Ross Westwood, Eugene White.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 12)
      Letters from: Shirley Williamson, Andrew Wille, Karen Wilson, Hilary Witt, Joe Wittreich and Stuart Curran, Kevin Wood.
    - Condolences: To Winston Wilde [not in WW's list]., circa 1995 (Box 54, Folder 13)
      Signed your loving son, Jack Hamilton, Jackie and Charles, Robert Lamont, Douglas Leleyte (?, San Francisco), unsigned letter (Pasadena).
    - Tributes, Obituaries, etc.: Committing to memory, by editor of Frontiers. In: Frontiers. vol.13 issue 22., March 10, 1995.; p.12. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Tributes, Obituaries, etc.: Afterlife: A Tribute to Paul Monette. In: Frontiers vol.13 issue 22., March 10, 1995.; pp.53-54, 56. (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Contributions from: Malcolm Boyd, Michael Kearns, Terry Wolverton, Michael Lassell, Elisabeth Nonas. With several portraits.
    - Tributes, Obituaries, etc.: Two Movies and a Memorial, by Michael Kearns. In: Edge. Issue 306., April 5, 1995.; p.53. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Tributes, Obituaries, etc.: ... This extraordinary and improbable honor ... To the editory from Nance Seale Osborne. In: Oswegonian. vol.60 no.9., 1995 April 6.; pp.9-10. (Box 55, Folder 4)
      Is commentary and text of PM's Oswego speech. With letter from Coy [Ludwig?].
    - Tributes, Obituaries, etc.: Author and Activist Paul Monette Remembered, by Dan Luckenbill. In: UCLA AIDS Institute Perspectives. vol.3 no.2., Summer 1995.; p.17. (Box 55, Folder 5)
      Reproduces portrait by Robert Giard (1988).
    - Tributes, Obituaries, etc.: Letter from Torie Osborne, enclosing obituary clippings., May 27, 1995. (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Calling Guidelines and Condolence Notes, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Press, Memorials, 1995 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Obituaries and Memorials, 1995-1997 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Correspondences, Monette/Horwitz Trust, 2003-2004 (Box 63, Folder 10)
- Series 3: Biographical, Photographs
  - Portrait: Education (?): PM in checked pants, bow tie, and holding wine glass. (Box 36, Folder 11)
    Is possibly from a play, or party(?).
  - Family/Education: Early School Years: Yearbook(?) (proofs?)., n.d.; 1 sheet (2 images). (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Education(?): Early School Years (?): Boys' school(?) group photograph., n.d.; 1 photograph. (Box 44, Folder 2)
    Seemingly teachers or coaches and varying aged boys.
  - Education: Phillips Academy: School play., n.d.; Black and white 8 × 10. 2 photographs. (Box 44, Folder 3)
    In Roman costumes. PM credits his acceptance to Yale to his participation in these plays. Cf. Becoming a Man, p.94.
  - Portraits: Photographer(s) Unknown: (?)., 1970s (Box 44, Folder 4)
    Seemingly 1970s haircuts.
  - Residence: East Coast (?): PM nude in field, in lumberjack checks, etc., n.d.; Snapshots. (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Also in some photographs: Cesar Albini.
  - Residence: East Coast (?): PM at beach, nude climbing rocks, etc., n.d.; Color snapshots. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Residence (?): East Coast (?): PM (nude) at beach., n.d.; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Residence/Travel: East Coast/Cape Cod, 1972-1973.; Snapshots. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Residence/Travel: Martha's Vineyard, 1973.; Color snapshots. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Relationship/Friendships: Roger Horwitz, etc.: East coast - Kings Road. Also some photographs San Francisco., 1977-1979.; From vertical album. (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Relationship/Friendships: Roger Horwitz, etc.: Various occasions., Color snapshots. From larger album. (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Relationship/Friendships: Roger Horwitz: PM, RH, Sheldon Andelson in tuxedos., Color enlargement. (Box 44, Folder 12)
    In cover, signed: Together on my fiftieth, Love, Shel 3 / 81.
  - Friendship: Susan ___ (?): PM: Susan's party. At Kings Road(?)., August 1982 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Relationship/Travel: Roger Horwitz: Florence (Italy) and Christmas (Kings Road)., December 1983.; Color snapshots. (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Relationship/Travel: Roger Horwitz: Florence (Italy) / copies of photograph used for Love Alone. (?)., December 1983; Color snapshots. (Box 44, Folder 15)
    Cf. Christopher Street, cover of Love Alone. Also: PM's Brother Robert.
  - Relationship/Friendships: Robert Monette, Roger Horwitz, Craig Rowland, and Jeff Henry: Getty Museum / also other shots Sunset Plaza, etc. Robert Monette is PM's brother., 1985.; Color snapshots. (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: Kings Road, Palisades (Santa Monica), etc., Summer 1985.; Color snapshots. (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Relationship/Travel: Roger Horwitz: Mass., Chicago. Roger's family, PM's home(?). (Date by PM)., Summer 1985; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Relationship/Travel: Roger Horwitz: Perloff party, Chicago. Also: Cesar Albini., summer 1985.; Color snapshots. (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: PM and RH., Snapshot enlargement. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: PM and RH., Proof sheet black and white. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: PM and RH clowning. (Box 45, Folder 3)
    Two images from take your own pictures.
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: PM and RH (dressy)., Black and white enlargement. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: RH and PM(?) backpacking., Black and white enlargement. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Relationship/Travel: Roger Horwitz: Big Sur., n.d.; Color snapshots. (Box 45, Folder 6)
    Copies of some of these prints were included in the album. Also: Cesar Albini.
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: PM, RH, and others. Kings Road(?) State Beach (Santa Monica Canyon), etc. Also: Cesar Albini., Color snapshots. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: RH, PM, and others, occasion unknown., Color snapshots. (Box 45, Folder 8)
    Last photographs of RH(?).
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: RH, PM. Seemingly selected photographs of RH, various occasions and locations. Also: Cesar Albini., 1987 (some prints) and n.d.; Color snapshots. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: East coast(?)., n.d.; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Relationship: Roger Horwitz: PM and RH, Kings Road(?) and Pacific Palisades., Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Relationship/Friendships: Roger Horwitz: Craig Rowland, Stephen Kolzak, and PM at display of Roger's quilt., Color snapshots. (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Travel: Taos: PM on horse, at D.H. Lawrence chapel, etc. Also: Star Black(?) (indistinct)., 1986.; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Friendship/Travel: Craig Rowland, East Coast(?): At country estate, at marina, etc. (some prints)., August 1987; Color snapshots, two sizes. (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Portraits: Robert Giard Photographer: PM in checked overshirt, by pool. 2 poses., 1988.; 8 × 10 black and white. 2 images. 3 items. With: c. 1988 Robert Giard in ink. (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Virginia Trip: ACT UP takeover of the FDA., October 1988.; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Portraits: Theodora Litsios Photographer: PM in front of bookcases, outside under pergola., 1988.; Contact prints black and white. (Box 45, Folder 17)
    Photo by Theodora Litsios c. 1988, 586 Matero St., Los Angeles ....
  - Relationship: Stephen Kolzak: Stevie K. aka Cotton Candy., Contact sheet black and white. (Box 45, Folder 18)
    SK in drag.
  - Relationship/Friendship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak, Craig Rowland, East Coast(?): PM, SK, CR, and unidentified woman. Seemingly East Coast., Color snapshots mounted on boards (2 items, 6 images). (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Friendship: Susan Graczyk (?): PM and SG birthday celebration. Also SK and others., October 16, 1989.; Color snapshots. (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Relationship: Stephen Kolzak: Christmas. (Date by PM)., 1989 or 1988; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Relationship: Stephen Kolzak: Christmas. (Date by PM)., 1989; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Relationship: Stephen Kolzak: Christmas. (Date by PM)., December 23, 1989; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Relationship: Stephen Kolzak: Christmas, New Year's. (Date by PM)., 1989; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/South Pacific: (Date by PM)., January 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/South Pacific: Tahiti. (Date by PM)., January 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/South Pacific: Tahiti New Year's. (Date by PM)., January 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: Caribbean and Topkapi Palace. (Date by PM)., February and June 1990; Color snapshots. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: PM and SK on board Stella Solaris Piraeus. (?)., June 1990; Color snapshot (enlarged). In Stella Solaris Sun Line folder. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: Greece, Turkey, Pergamon. (Date by PM)., June 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: Delos, Mykonos, Santorini. (Date by PM)., June 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: Turkey. (Date by PM)., June 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: Greece [Crete (Knossos), etc.]. (Date by PM)., June 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: Ephesus, Istanbul. (Date by PM)., June 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: Athens (Acropolis). (Date by PM)., June 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: Ephesus, Rhodes. (Date by PM)., June 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: Greece (unidentified). (Date by PM)., June 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Greece, etc.: Athens, Mykonos, Delos(?). (Date by PM)., June 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Relationship/Travel: Stephen Kolzak/Laguna Beach, California: In hotel, at the beach. (Date by PM)., August 1990; Color snapshots and negatives. (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Portraits: Photographer Unknown: PM in red sweater, all poses., n.d.; Color snapshots. (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Portraits: Photographer Unknown: PM in dressy leather jacket, outside in front of flowering branches., Black and white enlargement. (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Portraits: Photographer Unknown: PM in striped polo shirt. Outside Kings Road, Hollywood Hills(?). (?)., Late 1970s, early 1980s; Black and white, 5 × 7s and 8 × 10. (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Relationship/Portraits: Winston Wilde: PM being interviewed, with Winston Wilde(?). Photographer unknown., n.d.; Black and white 8 × 10 proof prints (on thin paper). (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Awards: Memoirs: Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story: PM at Library of Congress, speaking, and with Neil Baldwin and John Cole. Photograph by Jim Higgins Library of Congress., January 28, 1993. (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Portraits/Various Occasions: PM dressed in jean shirt with jeans with one hand on hip and the other hand up leaning against garage door (by Star Black): 1995 Addition, ca. 1978 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Friendships, Unidentified, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Friendships, Guru Ma Jaya, circa 1993 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Travel, Taos, NM, by Star Black, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Portraits by Star Black, circa 1988 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Portraits, Professional, by Robert Giard, Kelly Wise, and Theodora Litsios, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Portraits, Stephen Kolzak Period, 1990 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Relationship, Stephen Kolzak and Monette Together, 1990 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Relationship/Travel, Stephen Kolzak and Negatives, 1990 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Relationship, Stephen Kolzak Alone, 1953-1990 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Portraits, Painted by Don Bachardy, 1990 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Portraits, Winston Wilde Period, 1991-1994 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Relationship, Winston Wilde and Monette Together, 1991-1994 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Relationship/Friendships, Winston Wilde, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Relationship/Friendships, Winston Wilde, circa 1993 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Relationship, Winston Wilde Alone, 1991-1994 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Travel, Sonoma County, Starcross Community, circa 1994 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Various, Special Events, Including CUNY Degree Ceremony, circa 1993 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Ceremony, National Book Awards, Mary Oliver, Dorothy Allison, Drenka Willen, and Winston Wilde, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - Relationship, Winston Wilde, By Tom Bianchi, circa 1992 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Portraits, for "Last Watch of the Night" by Gay Block, and Correspondence, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - Relationship, Winston Wilde and Buddy, By Gay Block, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 21)
  - Relationship/Friendships/Travel, Winston Wilde and Gay Block, Italy, Keats' Grave, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 22)
  - Portraits/Relationship, Winston Wilde, By Gay Block, 1995 (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Friendships, John Rechy and Betty Berzon, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 24)
  - Relationship, Winston Wilde, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 25)
  - Portraits, By Star Black, and Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 56, Folder 26)
  - Family, 1944-1993 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Portraits, Baby, 1945-1947 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Portraits/Family, Boyhood, 1950-1957 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Family/Education, Yale Graduation, 1963-1967 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Portraits, 1968-1974 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Portraits, Nude Series, Possibly by Jack Speer, circa 1981 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Portraits, Roger Horwitz Period, 1974-1986 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Relationship/Travel, Roger Horwitz and Big Sur, 1980-1984 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Relationship/Travel, Roger Horwitz, Europe, Greece, circa 1983 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Relationship/Travel, Roger Horwitz, South of France and Delphi, Undated (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Travel, Europe, circa 1984 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Relationship, Roger Horwitz and Monette Together, 1979-1984 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Relationship, Roger Horwitz Alone and with Others, 1954-1986 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Relationship, Roger and his Family, including Beatrice and Sheldon Andelson, circa 1984 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Friendships, Cesar and Richard Ide, as well as Roger, 1977-1984 (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Relationship/Friendships, Roger, Roger's Parents, Robert Flick, Susan Rankaitis, Marjorie Perloff, Carol Muske, and Craig, circa 1982 (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Friendships, "Scarface" Novelization Launch, 1983 (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Friendships, Roger Horwitz and Susan Rankaitis, 1985 (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Various, Unidentified Locations and Kings Road, Undated (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Pets, Puck and Buddy, 1980-1994 (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Friendships, Emily, circa 1971 (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - Friendships, Virginia Howl, circa 1973 (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Friendships, Gertrude "Gerty" Macy, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 23)
  - Friendships, Kathleen, circa 1980 (Box 61, Folder 24)
  - Friendships, Sally, 1983 (Box 61, Folder 25)
  - Friendships, Star Black, Undates (Box 61, Folder 26)
  - Friendships, Craig, circa 1987 (Box 61, Folder 27)
  - Friendships, Gary Barton, 1988 (Box 61, Folder 28)
  - Friendships, Judith Light, circa 1990 (Box 61, Folder 29)
  - Negatives, Unidentified, Undated (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Portraits/Relationship/Friendships, "Brink of Summer's End," Contact Sheet Copies, circa 1994 (Box 64, Folder 3)
- Series 4: Writings
  - Subseries 4.1: Poetry
    - The Self-Winding Staircase: Poems / Paul Monette. Photocopy is: The Staircase., 1963-1965. n.d.; [46] leaves. Typescript. Also one leaf typescript (photocopy). (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - The Staircase: Fair copy(?)., n.d.; 1 leaf. Calligraphy, with the name Paul Monette, Jr. (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - "The Messengers of Sadness", undated (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Poems 1965-1970: Typescripts, notes., n.d.; 49 leaves total. (Box 9, Folder 4)
      PM: Poems from Yale & the years just after.
    - Hobo / The Technicolor Angel: Publication Material: In: Criterion (a Yale Literary Journal), edited by PM., January 1967. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Reviews, etc.: Newspapers not identified., 1970(?)-.; Clippings (newsprint) and photocopies. (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Newspaper published in Andover? (reverse of clippings has ads for businesses in Andover).
    - Sarah: Publication Material: In: Magazine., 1970.; 3 copies. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Sarah: Publication Material: Leaves from Magazine [section of 5 poems]., n.d. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Sarah: Post-Publication Material: Interview. Clipping: Lawrence Eagle Tribune., March 30, 1970. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Leaving Cheshire: For My Students: In: Midpoint, The Academy Review [Cheshire Academy, Cheshire, Connecticut]. (?)., 1970 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Early Poems: Various drafts and publications., 1972-1976, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 21)
      PM's description: Letters - manuscript. Early rejections, acceptances, etc. James Dickey, Daniel Halperin, Richard Howard, etc. Carpenter ... letters refiled.
    - Early Poems: Contracts, check stub., 1973, 1975, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - The Looker-On: Fra Angelico, Crucifixion, about 1450. By Paul Monette. Milton, Massachusetts: Chapbook Press, n.d. [per PM], ca. 1973; 3 folded leaves (unnumbered pages). (Box 9, Folder 23)
      Contains poems: 1. Friday, 2. Saturday, 3. Sunday.
    - "Getting to Walden": Milton, Massachusetts: Chap Book Press. Can be dated(?)., 1974 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - The Carpenter at the Asylum [Published September 1975]: Various drafts., 1973-1975 [per PM].; 76 leaves total. Typescript and holograph. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The Carpenter at the Asylum: Letters from editor, etc., April 1973-November 1974. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - The Carpenter at the Asylum: Reviews. Choice and Southwest Review., Spring 1976 and May 1976.; Clippings (photocopies). (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Spring 1976 signed by editor, not reviewer(?).
    - The Wedding Letter: Letter from Louis Untermeyer., February 28, 1977.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      On notepaper: from the desk of Louis Untermeyer ....
    - My Shirts: In: Christopher Street., October 1977. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      To Roger. Collected in No Witnesses.
    - No Witnesses / Getting On: Getting On., n.d.; [5] leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 10, Folder 9)
      From Poems / Drafts folder. No poem this title in No Witnesses volume. Never published [per PM].